<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>health | Madhav Sankaranarayanan</title>
    <link>https://madhav1812.github.io/tag/health/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://madhav1812.github.io/tag/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>health</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://madhav1812.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>health</title>
      <link>https://madhav1812.github.io/tag/health/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emulated trials in linked registry-claims data</title>
      <link>https://madhav1812.github.io/project/emulated-trial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://madhav1812.github.io/project/emulated-trial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In collaboration with Lidia Moura, Mila Sun, Julianne Brooks, Victor Lomachinsky Torres, Sebastien Haneuse and Mamoon Habib&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Older adults receive benzodiazepines for agitation, anxiety, and insomnia after acute ischemic stroke (AIS). No
trials have been conducted to determine if benzodiazepine use affects poststroke mortality in the elderly. Recent
work has concluded that there is no short-term mortality from benzodiazepine use post-acute ischemic stroke
in a local cohort of patients. We look to extend the analysis of mortality and other important outcomes to the
Medicare dataset, linked with insurance registry claims. We employ methodology from emulated trials liter-
ature to construct sophisticated models that account for semi-competing risks and overlapping observation times.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Middle Meningeal Artery Embolization in adjunction to surgical evacuation for treatment of subdural hematomas: A nationwide comparison of outcomes with isolated surgical evacuation</title>
      <link>https://madhav1812.github.io/project/middle-emb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://madhav1812.github.io/project/middle-emb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In collaboration with Mirhojjat Khorasanizadeh, Seyed Farzad Maroufi, Rajarshi Mukherjee, Justin M. Moore and Christopher S.Ogilvy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surgical evacuation is the standard treatment for chronic subdural hematomas (CSDHs) but is associated with
a high risk of recurrence and readmission. Middle meningeal artery embolization (MMAE) is a novel treatment
approach which could be performed upfront or in adjunction to surgical evacuation. MMAE studies are limited
by small sample sizes. This study aimed to describe and compare outcomes of MMAE in adjunction to surgery
with those of surgery alone on a national level.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
